BETHANY GROGG

South Berwick, ME 03908

Phone: 207-384-4156 | Email: Bethany.Grogg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bethany-grogg-809093b0/ | Github: https://github.com/BethGrogg

Portfolio: https://bethgrogg.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a background in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express and React programming. Database experience with MySQL and MongoDB. Previous experience with Java and COBOL. A team player who loves the challenge of creative problem solving but also loves working independently. Passionate about providing a positive user experience and thorough testing to provide quality web applications. Graduate of the University of New Hampshire's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp program.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Semantic UI, Firebase, AJAX, JSON, MySQL, Handlebars, Express, Node.js, React, Java

PROJECTS

SWARM | https://github.com/shimmer10/swarm | https://cryptic-harbor-20380.herokuapp.com/

- An application for agile teams with remote members to gather daily stand-up data.
- Created with react, react-bootstrap, passport, and canvasJS

2020 Election | https://github.com/rcreveling/project-one | https://creveling.github.io/project-one/

- An application for up-to-date, unbiased information about the 2020 elections.
- Developed the slider at the top of the page of relevant articles and the overall design of the application.
- Created with HTML, CSS, Materialize, Javascript, JQuery, Propublica APIs, New York Times API, canvasJS

Train Scheduler | https://github.com/BethGrogg/Train Scheduler | https://bethgrogg.github.io/Train Scheduler/

- An application that simulates train schedules and updating their information based on the current time.
- Created with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, moment.js.

EXPERIENCE

Special Education Educational Technician RSU 35

2015-2019

Eliot, ME

- One-to-one support for students,
- Problem-solver and effective communicator, often asked to assist with difficult situations.
- Recognized as dependable, flexible, and calm.
- Suggested a bus drop off plan that was successfully implemented, decreasing transitions for our students.

Software Engineer Liberty Mutual Insurance

2000-2005

Portsmouth, NH

• Two years BFT program, 3 years in Commercial Markets, mostly Java.

- Implemented a new system from start to finish, acting as Project Lead and developer.
- Recommended an update to the AutoID system front-end, increasing client satisfaction.

Information Systems Specialist Travelers Insurance Company

1997-2000

Hartford, CT

- Maintained a COBOL mainframe application.
- Y2K updates that allowed for a flawless move into the year 2000.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certification: University of New Hampshire

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Business-Focused Training (BFT): Liberty Mutual Insurance

A 2 year program designed to educate software engineers on different aspects of the business through internships with the program, culminating in a year long technical project.

Bachelor of Science in Dietetics: James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA